Fresh Fish. Mixed Vegetables.
Jonah: A VeggieTales Movie is a adventure, animation,
comedy film directed by Phil Vischer.
Get ready as Bob the Tomato, Larry the Cucumber and the rest of the Veggies set sail on a
whale of an adventure in Big Idea's first full-length, 3-D animated feature film.
This is the story of Jonah and the Whale as you've never seen it before - a story where we
learn that one of the best gifts you can give - or get - is a second chance.
Archibald Asparagus / Jonah / Twippo / Bob the Tomato / Mr. Lunt / Pirate Lunt / Percy Pea / Phillipe Pea / Pa
Grape / Pirate Pa / Nezzer / King Twistomer / Cockney Pea #2 (voice), played by Phil Vischer.
Larry the Cucumber / Pirate Larry / Jean Claude Pea / Cockney Pea #1 / Self-Help Tape
Voice / Jerry Gourd / Whooping BBQ Pea (voice), played by Mike Nawrocki.
Khalil (voice), played by Tim Hodge.
Junior Asparagus (voice), played by Lisa Vischer.
Dad Asparagus (voice), played by Dan Anderson.
Laura Carrot (voice), played by Kristin Blegen.
Jonah: A VeggieTales Movie is a 2002 American animated Christian musical comedy adventure film produced by
Big Idea Productions and released by Artisan Entertainment through its F·H·E Pictures label.
Written and directed by Phil Vischer and Mike Nawrocki in their feature directorial debuts, it is the first of the two theatrical
feature films in the VeggieTales series, before The Pirates Who Don't Do Anything: A VeggieTales Movie (2008).
The themes for the film are compassion and mercy, using two stories as illustrations linked by the Pirates Who
Don't Do Anything, who were first seen in the Silly Song of the same name in Very Silly Songs!.
The first story takes place in the current day and concerns a mishap with Bob the Tomato and Dad Asparagus on the
way to a concert; the second, set in ancient times, is based directly on the biblical story of Jonah.
Through both stories, compassion and mercy play a
role in giving people a second chance.
Jonah: A VeggieTales Movie premiered on August 14, 2002, and came out
as a regular release two months later on October 4.
It received generally positive reviews from critics, who praised the humor and narrative style, and grossed $25.6 million
against a $14 million production budget, making it the highest-grossing film released by Big Idea Productions.
The film came out on VHS and DVD on March 4, 2003, as a worldwide home video release in both
full-screen and anamorphic widescreen formats with a two-disc collector's edition.
A DVD reprint with the feature and bonus features was released on
Blu-ray in 2011 by Lionsgate (Artisan's successor).
The film explores themes of whale, forgiveness, musical, revenge, repentance.
The tone is lighthearted.